Register of the Robert Charles Hill papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ambassador to Argentina File, 1971-1977
  - Top News (Buenos Aires) newsletter issues, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 183: 29)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1947-1976
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some government records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2010 release of records, 1957-1976 (Reading room workstation)
    Scope and Contents note
    Primarily dispatches from the American embassy, Mexico, to Department of State, 1957-1960, as well as various memos, reports, and other records. Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2011 September release of records, 1955-1971
    - Memos, clippings, 1955-1971 (Box-folder 183: 30)
    - Briefing books, 1970 March (Box-folder 183: 31)
    - Briefing books, 1970 April (Box-folder 183: 32)
    - Briefing book - Argentina, 1975 (Box-folder 183: 33)
    - Contacts in Mexico, 1957 (Box-folder 183: 34)
    - Personnel reports, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 183: 35)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1969-1970
      - Benton, William, 1970 (Box-folder 183: 36)
      - Braggiotti, D. Chadwick, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 183: 37)
      - Bishop, Max W., 1971 (Box-folder 183: 38)
      - Leddy, Raymond G., 1970 (Box-folder 183: 39)
      - Lodge, John Davis, 1969 (Box-folder 183: 40)
      - Rickover, Hyman G., 1969 (Box-folder 183: 41)
  - 2015 release of records, 1947 (Box-folder 183: 42)
    Records consist of a transcript of hearings before the Comittee on Banking and Currency of the United States Senate
- Scrapbooks, 1953-1978
  Correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, press releases, and printed matter, arranged chronologically.
  - Costa Rica and El Salvador, 1953 October-1955 July (Box 184)
  - Mexico, 1957-1960
    - 1957 March-1958 July (Box 185)
    - Visits to consulates, 1957 December-1958 March (Box 186)
    - 1958 July-1959 May (Box 187)
    - 1959 June-September (Box 188)
    - 1959 September-October (Box 189)
    - 1959 October-December (Box 190)
    - 1959 June-1960 February (Box 191)
    - 1960 February-August (Box 192)
    - 1960 August-November (Box 193)
  - Mexico and U.S., 1960 July-1962 June (Box 194)
  - U.S., 1960-1969
    - 1960 December-1962 December (Box 195)
    - 1963 January-1964 September (Box 196)
    - 1964 October-1966 December (Box 197)
    - 1966 October-1968 August (Box 198)
    - Crawford House, N.H., 1967 January-1969 March (Box 199)
    - 1968 June-1969 May (Box 200)
  - Spain, 1969-1971
    - 1969 April-1970 August (Box 201)
    - 1970 August-1971 December (Box 202)
  - Spain and U.S., 1971 February-1974 February (Box 203)
  - Argentina, 1973-1977
    - 1973 December-1974 February (Box 204)
    - 1974 February-1976 July (Box 205)
    - 1974 March-July (Box 206)
    - 1974 August-December (Box 207)
    - 1975 January-April (Box 208)
    - 1975 May-December (Box 209)
    - 1976 July-December (Box 210)
    - 1977 January-July (Box 211)
  - U.S., 1977 July-1978 November (Box 212)
- Sound Recordings, 1960-1972
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Speech to American Legion national convention, Miami, Fla., 1960 October 19 (Tape 1)
  - Speech relating to Mexico, circa 1960s (Tape 2)
  - Radio broadcast on taxation in New Hampshire, 1972 February 18 (Tape 3)
  - Speech to Rotary Club, Newport, N.H., 1972 May 3 (Tape 4)
- Motion Picture Film, 1955-1972, undated
  - "Treasure of the Tropics," United Fruit Company film, undated (Reel 1)
  - "Inter-American Highway," U.S. Information Service film of the automobile trip of Robert C. Hill from El Salvador to the U.S., 1955 (Reel 2)
  - Newsreel film of Robert C. Hill in Mexico, circa 1957-1960 (Reel 3)
  - "Flags of Friendship," U.S. Information Service film of the visit of President Adolfo Lopez Mateos of Mexico to the U.S., 1959 (Reel 4)
  - "Great First Ladies," Film of the Great Lady Fashion Show, Republican National Convention Chicago, 1960 (Reel 5)
  - Film of Robert C. Hill at El Cordobes Finca, Cordoba, Spain, 1971 (Reel 6)
  - "Return to Menorca," U.S. Naval Air Systems Command film, 1971 (Reel 7)
  - "New Hampshire Primaries 1972," U.S. Information Service film (Reel 8)
  - "Elections 1972," U.S. Information Service film (Reel 9)
- Photographs, 1941-1977
  - Album of photographs of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, taken by Life photographers, 1960 (Album fA)
  - Album of photographs of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, with various Mexican and American officials, 1957-1958 (Album fB)
  - Album of photographs of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, with various Mexican and American officials, 1958-1960 (Album fC)
  - Album of photographs of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, with various Mexican and American officials, 1960 (Album fD)
  - Album of photographs of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, taken on a visit to Guadalajara, circa 1957-1960 (Album fE)
  - 53 prints of launchings of ships constructed by the New England Shipbuilding Corporation in Portland, Maine, 1941-1944 (Envelope F)
  - 90 prints of stages in construction of ships built by the New England Shipbuilding Corporation, Portland, Maine, 1943-1944 (Envelope G-H)
  - 1 print of a U.S. Foreign Service class, 1944, including Dean Acheson as an instructor; and 23 prints of Robert C. Hill as a vice consul, taken in India and Burma, 1944-1945 (Envelope I)
  - 7 prints of Robert C. Hill as a businessman, circa 1947-1953 (Envelope J)
  - 13 prints of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Costa Rica, 1953-1954 (Envelope K)
  - 40 prints of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to El Salvador, with unidentified Salvadoran officials, 1954-1955 (Envelope L)
  - 6 prints of Robert C. Hill at the U.S. Department of State with visitors and U.S. Senators, 1956-1957 (Envelope M)
  - 9 portraits of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico, circa 1957-1960 (Envelope N)
  - 20 prints and 1 negative of Robert C. Hill and family with President Dwight D. Eisenhower upon the occasion of Hill's appointment as Ambassador to Mexico, 1957 (Envelope O)
  - 4 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of State John Foster Dulles, 1957; 1 print of Robert C. Hill with Pope John XXIII, 1959; and 1 portrait of Admiral Emory Land, 1957-1959, undated (Envelope P)
  - 10 oversize prints of Robert C. Hill at a Fourth of July celebration in Mexico, 1959 (Envelope mQ)
  - 21 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Celaya, Mexico, 1959 (Envelope R)
  - 2 prints of a CARE well-drilling project in San Mateo Atenco, Mexico, 1959 (Envelope S)
  - 5 prints of Robert C. Hill with Admiral Manuel Zermeno Araico in Mexico, 1959 (Envelope T)
  - 6 prints of Robert C. Hill with Admiral Manuel Zermeno Araico in Mexico, 1959 (Envelope U)
  - 10 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting the offices of the Mexico City Daily Bulletin, 1957 (Envelope V)
  - 5 prints of Robert C. Hill with General Matias Ramos Santos, Mexican Secretary of National Defense, other Mexican generals, and U.S. Congressman Don Jackson, 1957 (Envelope W)
  - 20 prints of Mrs. Robert C. Hill and wives of other prominent Republicans appearing in the Great Lady Fashion Show, Republican National Convention, Chicago, 1960 (Envelope X)
  - 40 prints of an expedition in the Himalayas led by Tom Slick in search of the yeti, 1953 (Envelope Y)
  - 283 prints of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Mexico with unidentified Mexican and American officials, circa 1957-1960 (Envelope Z-AE)
  - 13 prints of the inauguration of President Richard M. Nixon, and of Secretary of State William P. Rogers with Robert C. Hill upon the occasion of his appointment as Ambassador to Spain, 1969 (Envelope AF)
  - 4 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of the Navy John Chafee in Spain, 1969 (Envelope AG)
  - 15 prints of demonstrators protesting the Vietnam War at the U.S. Embassy in Madrid, 1969 (Envelope AH)
  - 16 prints of the visit to Spain of Apollo 11 astronauts, 1969 (Envelope AI)
  - 8 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Valencia, Spain, 1969 (Envelope AJ)
  - 52 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Palma de Mallorca, Spain, 1969 (Envelope AK)
  - 31 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Barcelona, Spain, 1969 (Envelope AL)
  - 6 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting the Robledo de Chavela tracking station, Spain, 1969 (Envelope AM)
  - 21 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Cordoba, Spain, 1970 (Envelope AN)
  - 13 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Sevilla, Spain, 1970 (Envelope AO)
  - 25 prints of Robert C. Hill with President Richard M. Nixon, Secretary of State William Rogers, Generalissimo Francisco Franco and Prince Juan Carlos in Spain, 1970 (Envelope AP)
  - 2 oversize prints of President Richard M. Nixon in Spain, 1970 (Envelope mAQ)
  - 3 prints of Robert C. Hill with F. Donald Nixon in Spain, 1970 (Envelope AR)
  - 11 prints of Robert C. hill and Foreign Minister Gregorio Lopez Bravo of Spain signing the U.S.-Spanish treaty of friendship and cooperation in Madrid, 1970 (Envelope AS)
  - 14 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of Defense Melvin Laird, Generalissimo Francisco Franco and Foreign Minister Gregorio Lopez Bravo in Spain, 1970 (Envelope AT)
  - 3 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of State William P. Rogers in Spain, 1970 (Envelope AU)
  - 5 prints of Robert C. Hill with Generalissimo Francisco Franco and Prince Juan Carlos at the International Agricultural Fair in Madrid, 1970 (Envelope AV)
  - 3 prints of Robert C. Hill with Jaime Arguelles, Spanish Ambassador to the U.S, 1970 (Envelope AW)
  - 1 print of Robert C. Hill with the Duchess of Alba in Spain, 1970 (Envelope AX)
  - 2 prints of Robert C. Hill with Mayor Carlos Arias Navarro of Madrid, 1970 (Envelope AY)
  - 15 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of Commerce Maurice H. Stans and Generalissimo Francisco Franco in Spain, 1971 (Envelope AZ)
  - 2 prints of Robert C. Hill with Admiral Thomas H. Moorer in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BA)
  - 3 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Menorca, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BB)
  - 6 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of Transportation John A. Volpe and Generalissimo Francisco Franco in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BC)
  - 18 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Galicia, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BD)
  - 2 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Santiago de Compostela, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BE)
  - 6 prints of Robert C. Hill with Prince Juan Carlos and President Richard M. Nixon in the U.S., 1971 (Envelope BF)
  - 2 prints of Robert C. Hill at the wedding of Tricia Nixon and Edward Cox, 1971 (Envelope BG)
  - 74 prints of Robert C. Hill at the Sherry Festival, Jerez de la Frontera, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BH)
  - 12 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting Huelva, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BI)
  - 4 prints of Robert C. Hill visiting the Peralta brothers' ranch, Spain, 1971 (Envelope BJ)
  - 5 prints of Robert C. Hill with Vice President Spiro T. Agnew, Generalissimo Francisco Franco and Prince Juan Carlos in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BK)
  - 4 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of Housing and Urban Development George Romney and Generalissimo Francisco Franco in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BL)
  - 1 print of Robert C. Hill with Ralph E. Forte, American journalist in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BM)
  - 4 prints of Robert C. Hill with Minister of Information and Tourism Alfredo Sanchez Bella of Spain and Spanish radio and television officials, 1971 (Envelope BN)
  - 1 print of Robert C. Hill receiving the Iberian Daily Sun Golden Award, 1971 (Envelope BO)
  - 12 prints of portraits by the Spanish painter Cristobal Toral, undated (Envelope BP)
  - 2 prints of portraits by the Spanish painter Carmen Laffon, undated (Envelope BQ)
  - 59 prints of Robert C. Hill with the Spanish bullfighter Manuel Benitez (El Cordobes) and Presidential Counselors Rober H. Finch and Donald Rumsfeld in Spain, 1971 (Envelope BR)
  - 13 prints of Robert C. Hill with U.S. Air Force officers at Torrejon Air Base, Spain, circa 1969-1971 (Envelope BS)
  - 1 print of President Dwight D. Eisenhower and Generalissimo Francisco Franco; 2 prints of Spanish cabinet ministers, circa 1969-1971; 2 prints of Robert C. Hill with Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare Elliot L. Richardson, 1971; 1 print of Presidential counselors Robert H. Finch and Donald Rumsfeld, 1971. 1 print of President Richard M. Nixon with Richard V. Allen and family; and 1 print of Anna Chennault, Attorney General John Mitchell, Secretary of the Interior Walter Hickel and Senator Ted Stevens, 1969 (Envelope BT)
  - 162 prints of Robert C. Hill as Ambassador to Spain, with unidentified Spanish and American officials, 1969-1971 (Envelope BU-BV)
  - 7 prints of Robert C. Hill with President Alfredo Stroessner of Paraguay and U.S. Ambassador to Paraguay George Landau, 1973 (Envelope BW)
  - 9 prints of Rober C. Hill with President Juan Peron and Foreign Minister Alberto J. Vignes of Argentina, 1974, and of anti American vandalism at the U.S. Embassy in Buenos Aires, circa 1974-1977 (Envelope BX)
  - 31 miscellaneous prints and prints of Robert C. Hill with unidentified individuals, undated (Envelope BY)
  - 1 oversize portrait of Robert C. Hill, undated (Envelope mBZ)